<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT AUTHOR="" DATE="2024-07-25T08:46:55+01:00"
    FORMAT="3.0" VERSION="3.0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAFv3.0.xsd">
    <HEADER MEDIA_FILE="" TIME_UNITS="milliseconds">
        <MEDIA_DESCRIPTOR
            MEDIA_URL="file:///Y:/WIBARAB/Terlan/Aufnahmen/FINAL FINAL/Zaer_Had L Ghwalem/Ghwalem_worker_life and a joke_2023/Zaer_Rommani from Ghwalem_worker_life and a joke_2023.WAV"
            MIME_TYPE="audio/x-wav" RELATIVE_MEDIA_URL="./Zaer_Rommani from Ghwalem_worker_life and a joke_2023.WAV"/>
        <PROPERTY NAME="URN">urn:nl-mpi-tools-elan-eaf:225f2482-2201-4769-9080-564666b8594b</PROPERTY>
        <PROPERTY NAME="lastUsedAnnotationId">24</PROPERTY>
    </HEADER>
    <TIME_ORDER>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts1" TIME_VALUE="13803"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts2" TIME_VALUE="42230"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts3" TIME_VALUE="42230"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts4" TIME_VALUE="83958"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts5" TIME_VALUE="101315"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts6" TIME_VALUE="134077"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts7" TIME_VALUE="135281"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts8" TIME_VALUE="165880"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts9" TIME_VALUE="166046"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts10" TIME_VALUE="203154"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts11" TIME_VALUE="203333"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts12" TIME_VALUE="253413"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts13" TIME_VALUE="253617"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts14" TIME_VALUE="286543"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts15" TIME_VALUE="286688"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts16" TIME_VALUE="344200"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts17" TIME_VALUE="344300"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts18" TIME_VALUE="412230"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts19" TIME_VALUE="412686"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts20" TIME_VALUE="471955"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts21" TIME_VALUE="472365"/>
        <TIME_SLOT TIME_SLOT_ID="ts22" TIME_VALUE="541386"/>
    </TIME_ORDER>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Terlan" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Phrases "
        PARTICIPANT="MOR_Z_Gh_39.M " TIER_ID="MOR_Z_Gh_39.M">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a2"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts1" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[mən aš mən qbila nta?] mən Zʕir, ḥna mən qbilat Zʕir, yăʕni ʕădd-na waḥəd-əl-suq, ta-ygulu li-h suq əl-ḥădd əl-ġwaləm. [yăʕni l-făxḍa dyal ġwaləm?] (lla, l-qbila d-əl-ġwaləm.) lla, ḍ-ḍŭwwaṛ dyal-na, ḥna ḍ-ḍŭwwaṛ šluḥa. yăʕni hadak əl-ḥădd dyal-na l-usbuʕi, huwa ta-ygulu li-h əl-ḥădd, ima l-qbila dyal-na, fin saknin, ḍŭwwaṛ š-šluḥa. ḍŭwwaṛ š-šluḥa, hadak huwa ḍ-ḍŭwwaṛ, fin zədna w-fin kbərna w-fin ...</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a3"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts3" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts4">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>fin qrina w-fin ... [w-ism əl-qbila?] əl-qbila ta-ygulu li-ha ... əl-ġwaləm, hiya, əl-aṣl dyal-ha l-ġwaləm, walakun kayn, kayn ši ḍwawəṛ li-huma bḥal daba kayn əl-gdadra ... kayn əl-gdadra, kaynin əl-ʕbabsa, kaynin Wlad ʕŭmran, kaynin ... smit-u hadak Wlad ʕli, kaynin əl-Xwaril ... ṣafi w-ma min-na ḥnaya lhih kayn, ʕawd tani, nawaḥi dyal Mulay Bu ʕăzza. šluḥ haduk bʕăd ʕli-na ḥnaya, yăʕni qbayl b-waḥdit-hum haduk.</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a5"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts5" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>kayna had əl-ġwaləm ġir fi qariya waḥda, ʕawd tani, hadik zhăyliga wəlla ṛŭṃṃani, ʕawd tani, b-waḥdit-hum haduk, ta-ykun, ʕawd tani, qbila b-waḥdit-hum haduk, yăʕni had əl-qbila hadi, had əl-qbila dyal l-Ġwaləm fi-had əḍ-ḍŭwwaṛ, gəlt lə-k, əl-Gdadra, əl-ʕbabsa, ḍŭwwaṛ Šluḥa, əl-xwarin, ši ṛəbʕat əl-qbayl wəlla xămsa. hadu huma, lli fi ḥădd əl-Ġwaləm, w-kayna, ʕawd tani, Wad Zam, kayna Zhăyliga, haduk bʕăd ʕli-na ḥna, maši f-əl-qbila dyal-na ...</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a6"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts7" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[kayna ʕalaqat aw ṭaṭa mʕa qbail uxṛayn?] kifaš zăʕma, ana ʕănd-i mʕa ši qăbail ŭxṛayn ... kənt xrəžt l ..., xrəžt əl-blad ana, xrəžt mən had əl-ġwaləm w-mšit, hažərt, šḥal dŭwwəzt f-ṣ-ṣăḥra, f-əl-ʕyun ... [walakin kayna ṭaṭa?] ma-ʕănd-i-š ʕaila təmma. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a7"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts9" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[waš kayna ʕadat xaṣṣa?] kaynin ... kaynin ʕadat, kayn waš f-əl-akl, f-əl-ʕras, f-əl-žtimaʕat ... kaynin ʕras, kaynt-na daba l-ʕărs, kayn əl-ʕărs dyal-na, kayn daba kullu w-kifaš ydir əl-ʕărs dyal-u, ta-yžib, t-ymšiw yxăṭbu hadik əl-bănt, ta-yʕṭiw waḥəd əl-... matal, waḥəd əl-mablaġ, fhəmti? waḥəd sətt alaf dərham aw xăms alaf dərham aw ăṛbəʕ alaf dərham w-ta-yəmši hadak əl-ʕris, ta-yəbši yaxŭd tta huwa dak əl-ḥwăyžat dyawl-ha w-f-əl-ʕărs ...</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a8"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts11" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ta-yž ... tta l-ʕărs ta-ydiru huma, ŭṃṃat ... lə-mṛa ... ta-ydiru l-ʕărs taqalid dyal-hum, š-štiḥ, əl-ʕiyalat, w-ta-yḥănniw li-ha w-ta-y... ydiru li-ha ta-y... hadak əl-... smit-u l-naqš, w-hadi w-dik-əl-lʕiba dyal hnaya, dak əl-... fhəmti? w-ta-ybqu yšəṭḥu ʕli-ha w-yġănniw ʕli-ha, ʕrist-na ... tkun ʕănd-ha ši smiya, hiya bḥal la faṭima wəlla Mina, Amina, əl-măṛḍiya kkʷa ykuru bnat ər-ržal măhdiya ... ta-yġănniw ʕla tta l-ʕris šwiya w-šwiya, ʕawd tani, ta-ydiru waḥəd-ət-tbəg w-ta-yḥăṭṭu fug mən-nu waḥəd-əḷ-ḷizaṛ, w-ta-ybqaw yăʕṭi-hum haduk əl-ftuḥ bḥal la ti-... ta-yʕṭiw waḥəd šwiya ši baraka dyal l-flus, ṣafi w-ta-yžəmʕu-hum w-haduk əl-flus, lli ta-yžəmʕu-hum, ta-ddi-hum hadik əl-ʕris. f-əl-lil ta-yži ḍăwṛ dyal l-ʕris. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a9"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts13" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts14">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>w-dak ḍ-ḍăwṛ dyal l-ʕris tta huwa ta-yʕṛăḍ ʕla n-nas, ʕla l-qăbail, kayn, lli ta-yži ʕla ... ʕla ... ʕla ʕud, ʕla siyara, ʕla ṃuṭuṛ, kayn, lli ta-yži ʕla rəžl-u, ta-yžiw mʕa l-ʕšiya, ta-yžiw, w-kayn, lli ta-yədbăḥ, ta-ykun ʕănd-u l-flus w-di... w-ta-ydəbḥu l-bhaym, ta-ydiru š-šwa, kayn, lli ma-ta-ykun-š ʕădd-u, ʕawd tani, ta-ydir ʕa šri l-lḥăm w-ta-ytăyyəb w-yžibu š-šiyax, haduk ṃwalin əl-kamanža, w-š-šixat w-... w-tsabu n-nas ybqaw yrăqṣu w-ynăšṭu, fhəmti? w-tani məlli ta-ylăhgu ʕa ... ta-ytʕăššaw, ta-ynuḍu, ʕawd tani, ta-yġăṛmu li-hum əl-flus.                                                </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a10"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts15" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts16">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>fhəmti? bḥal daba, anaya răšid, ʕa răšid, ha huwa ʕṭa-k ṛəbʕ alaf riyal, ḷḷa yəxləf, w-yḥŭṭṭ-ha f-t-tbəg. fhəmti? yăʕni ta-yʕăwḍu li-hum. w-hada huwa tăqalid dyal-na ʕna. ʕawd tani, f-l-makla, ʕawd tani, ʕla ḥăsab, kəskəsu, š-šwa, ḥna măʕṛufin b-əš-šwa, ta-nšŭwwu ši dyal š-šwa dyal l-lḥăm. hadi hiya zʕir baš măʕṛufa, b-š-šwa w-l-kəskəsu w-... smit-ha, w-r-rfisa, b-dək əl-zəbda w-... fhəmti? hada huwa, lli baš măʕṛufin. w-ẓ-ẓṛăʕ, ʕawd tani, əl-xuḍaṛ, ʕawd tani, ʕawd tani, ta-ydiru dak-ši dyal l-xuḍaṛ wəlla ... hada huwa, lli kayn ʕădd-na hnaya, ṣafi. hadi hiya l-ʕadat, lli kayna. [tbəddlət l-ʕadat f-əl-ʕrasat? kifaš kant bəkri?] kan bəkri, kan hna ta-yəmši l-răžəl gaʕ, ta-yəbši ʕad s-sid. d-dərri ma-ta-yʕṛăf, lla d-dərriya, lla walu. fhəmti? </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a11"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts17" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts18">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>ta-yəmši ʕădd-u, ta-ygul li-h "dak əd-dərriya bġit nddi-ha l wəldi" huwa hadi, ṣafi, ma-t-ytfăhmu-š, yăʕni d-dərri ma-ta-yšuf lla d-dərriya, lla walu. ta-ylăʕbu ġir walidi-hum, huma lli ty... ta-yžibu-ha ṣafi, ʕawd tani, ḅhal-ŭk, ḅhal la ma-ka-ydiru-š tta l-kaġt waḥəd-əl-wăqt, walakin daba ṭṭăwwrat, fhəmti? ṭṭăwwrat əl-wăqt daba wəlla l- qawanin wəlla ... had-ši, lli kayn daba. hadu huma l-ʕadat ... [kifaš ka-yʕiš ždud-kum?] ždud-na, ta-yʕawdu l-na ʕa walidi-na, ʕa kan, ʕawd tani, wahəd-əl-wăqt f... dyal, hadu, lli ta-yʕawdu l-na ḥna. ʕa ta-yʕawdu l-na. ma-šəfna-š ġir əl-walid w-hadi ta-yʕawd ... kant l-hna, yăʕni, kan waḥət xir f-bnadəm l-waʕi šwiya. kant əl-ʕrubiya, kant n-niya, fhəmti? w-bnadəm ta-ydeppane băʕdiyat-u, lli ma-ʕădd-u-š yăʕṭi l hada, ma-ʕădd-ik-š gaʕ əl-blad "aži w-skŭn!", fhəmti? daba lla. wəllat kull, lli ʕănd-u ši-ḥaža, hiya, lli ġa yṛăyyəḥ bi-ha. ma-ʕădd-ək-š ṛa-h ma-ʕănd-ək walu. yăʕni tbəddlat mən hadak əl-wăqt l daba, ṛa-h, ʕawd tani, hăyf xŭṛ. hadi huwa, lli kbərna bi-h ḥna. daba w-had-ši, lli ta-yʕawdu l-na walidi-na. had-ši, lli kayn. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a12"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts19" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts20">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[waš ka-tʕăṛfi l-xurafat aw qiṣaṣ dyal qbila dyal-kum?] lla, ma... tta ana ... ṛa-h ... warakun ma-... warakun ma-ʕăṛft-š ana, ma-tʕăṛf-š nḥažiya dak ... (ʕa ḥaži li-ya, nḥaži li-ha, gul!) aš ngul lə-k, a xti. (dyal-aš, ši ḥăžžaya.) wa-yəḥ daba ši ḥăžžaya ta-ybqaw ygulu l-ək. aš ġa ngul lə-k, w-ḷḷahi, ma-ʕăṛfţ ... (ʕa gul, gul ši ḥăžžaya, na ʕawtt li-ha ʕla ḥăžžayat-na! ʕawd li-na nta ḥăžžayat-kum f-əl-ġwaləm, aš mən ḥăžžayat-kum ... ) w-ḷḷahi, ma-ʕṛăft, ana ma-... (tfăkkər! tfăkkər!) kaynin ... aš ta-ygul l-ək daba, ʕawt tani, a wəddi, tləft, tləft, ma-... (ʕa gul! gul! tfăkkər!) tləft ʕla dak-ši, ma-bqăyt-š ʕaqəl ... w-ḷḷah, qa-š ʕădd-na dak-ši. kant ... tḥažina waḥəd žədda w-hadi, fhəmti? sqat haži li-na, warakun daba ḥna bqina-š ʕaqlin walu ... [waš ka-tʕăṛfi ši nukta?] </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a13"
                TIME_SLOT_REF1="ts21" TIME_SLOT_REF2="ts22">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>nŭkta? ... b-lati, nšuf dak-ši ... daba ... hada waḥəd, waḥəd ... waḥəd-əl-ʕduza, mṛa kbira, ta-tži ʕădd wəld-ha ta-tbqa dgul li-h ... tbqa dgul li-h: "ṃṃu-k dima ta-tʕăyyər-ni, fhəmti, w-ta-tsəbb-ni w-hadi" ... w-yži ʕănd-a, dak əl-mṛa dyal-a, gal l-ha "šufi, ana ġadi nži ġa nbqa nḍṛŭb fi-k, nḍrŭb fi-k w-mənni tti nbda nḍrŭb f-l-mxădda, ʕa f-l-mxădda bqăy tġăwwti. qat ta-tġăwwət w-hadi sa galt daba w-hiya txŭrž ʕădd-u ṃṃu galt li-h "a bərrəti li-ya gəlb-i, a wəld-i" ṣafi gal li-ha "mama, šufi, ġədda ana ġadi nəmši, ġa nsədd ʕli-ha f-əḍ-ḍaṛ w-ġa nxălli-ha, ntiya ... hiya nxălli-ha ṛa-h ma ġa takŭl", ma ġa nqas sădd ʕli-ha f-əḍ-ḍaṛ. huwa həzz-ha dda-ha mʕa-h, dda mʕa-h mṛat-u. ža ʕšiya, gal li-ha "l-walida, a mdra?", gəlt li-h "a ṛa-h xălliti li-ya w-ta-ṭŭḷḷ li-ya məl l-tăḥt w-mən ṣ-ṣwaḥ, w-hiya ta-tʕăyyər b(w)i-ha mən tăḥt hadak əl-bab" w-hiya ṛa-h dda-ha [...] aywa ṣafi, hada huwa l-ḥažžaya. wa-ʕănd-i bəzzaf ġir ana tləft w-ḷḷahi ma-ʕṛəff-š, tləft ana ma-bqin-aš ʕaqlin ʕla had-ši. 

</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </ALIGNABLE_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Words"
        PARENT_REF="MOR_Z_Gh_39.M" PARTICIPANT="A" TIER_ID="A_Words-txt"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="MOR_Z_Gh_39.M" PARTICIPANT="A" TIER_ID="A_Translation-gls-en">
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a14" ANNOTATION_REF="a2">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[From which tribe are you?] From Zaer, we are from the tribe of Zaer, this means we have a market, they call it suq l-hadd (sunday market) of the Ghwalem. [This means the faxda is Ghwamlem?] (No, the tribe is Ghwalem.) No, our village, we are the village Shluha. This means that is our weekly sunday, it, they call it l-hadd, but our tribe, where we live, is the village Shluha. The village Shluha, that is the village, where we were born and where we grew up and where ... </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a15" ANNOTATION_REF="a3">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Where we learned and where ... [And the name of the tribe?] The tribe, they call it ... Ghwalem, its origin is the Ghwalem, but there are some other villages, like there is Gdadra ... there is Gdadra, there are the Ababsa, there are the Wlad Umran, there are ... it's name of that is Wlad Ali, there are Chwaril ... that's it, and far from us, over there, also, in the direction of the Mulay Bu Azza, These are Shluh, far from us, this means there are specific tribes. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a16" ANNOTATION_REF="a5">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>This Ghwalem is only in one village, also, Zhiliga or Rommani, also they are seperated, they are, also, seperated tribes, this means this tribe, this one, it is the tribe of Ghwalem in this village, I told you, the Gdadra, the Ababsa, the village Shluha, the Chwarin, around four or five tribes. These are the ones, who are in the periphery of Ghwalem, and there is also, Wad Zam, there is Zhiliga, they are far from us here, they are not in our tribe ... </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a17" ANNOTATION_REF="a6">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[Are relations or tata with another tribe?] How? Me, I have with other tribes ... I was out ... I left the region, I left this l-Ghwalem and went, I emigrated, a long time I spend in the Sahara, in Laayun ... [But is there a tata?] I don't have a family there. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a18" ANNOTATION_REF="a7">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[Are there special traditions?] There are ... there are traditions, there is food for weddings, in social gatherings ... there are weddings, there was a wedding, there is our wedding, there is everything now and how one does his wedding, he brings, they go to engage this girl, they bring a ... some money, do you understand? Around six or five thousand dirham or four thousand dirham and that groom goes, he also goes to take  her clothes and at the wedding ... </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a19" ANNOTATION_REF="a8">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He ... also they make weddings, the mother ... the wife ... they make a traditonal wedding for them, dances, the women, they put henna on her and they... they make for her ... this ... it's called naqsh, and these things from here, this ... do you understand? They keep dancing and singing for her, our bride ...she has a name, like Fatima or Mina, Amina, she is blesses from her parents, so are the daughters of the man, she is rightful ... they also sing for the groom a little, also, they make a big plate on it and they put a fabiric on it, they keep giving them presents like if ... they give a little money as baraka, that's it, they gather them and this money, which they collected for them, she gives it (the money) to the groom. In the night its the turn of the groom. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a20" ANNOTATION_REF="a9">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>The turn of the groom, also he invites people, the tribes. There are, who come with ... with ... with horses, with cars, motorbikes, there are, who come by feet, they come in the evening, they come, there are, who slaughter (a cattle), the ones having money and ... they slaughter cattle, they make a barbeque, there are, who don't have anything, also, they buy meat and cook it and they bring dancers, these kamanja players, dancers and ... ??? the people keep dancing and having fun, do you understand? And than, when they reach just ... they have dinner, they get up and than, they collect money for them. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a21" ANNOTATION_REF="a10">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>Do you understand? Like now, I am Rashid, that's Rashid also he gave four thaousand riyal, God rewards him, and he put it on the plate. Do you understand? This means they reward them, and that is our tradition here. Also, the food, also, depending on the opportunities, couscous, barbeque, here we are famous for barbeque, we make barbeque of meat. This is what Zaer is famous for, for barbeque and couscous and ... it's name is, rfisa, with this butter and ... do you understand? This is it, what for it is famous. And wheat, also, the vegetables, also, also they make something out of vegetables ... These are our traditions, which we have. [Did the traditions for weddings changed?] There was in the past, here the man went, he went to the father. The guy didn't know, nor the girl, knew nothing, do you understand?</ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a22" ANNOTATION_REF="a11">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>He goes to him and says: "This girl, I want to take her for my son." This is it, thats it, they didn't talk to each other, this means the boy didn't see neither the girl nor anything. Only the parents were doing it for them, they are the ones, who ... they bring her, thats it, also, like this, like this, they didn't make papers at times, but now it developed, do you understand? It developed, now it is all lawful or ... this is, what there is. These are the traditions ... [How did your ancestors lived?] Our ancestors, our parents told us about it  , also there was a time in which ... of, these, whom, they told us about them. We didn't see anyone except our parents, and they told us ... Here was peace, so, there was a good among the people and a little consciousness. There was the countryside, there was sincerity, do you understand? And the people helped each other, who has nothing, one gives him that, you don't have land at all "come and live!", do you understand? Now, no. It became that everyone, who has something, everyone lives with what he got. (If) you don't have anything, than you have nothing. This means it changed from this time to now. See, also, another spirit. That is, how we grew up here. Now that is, what our parents told us. This is, what there is. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a23" ANNOTATION_REF="a12">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>[Do you know any myths or stories about your tribe?] No, no ... also me ... look ... but ... but I don't know, how to tell you this myths ... (Just tell me a myth, I will tell her, tell!) What to tell you, my sister. (Anything, any story.) Yeah, now some myths, they keep telling it to you. What to tell you, by God, I don't know ... (Just tell, tell a story, I told her about our fairy tales. Tell us a fairy tell from the Ghawlem, which fairy tales do you have...) By God, I don't know, I don't ... (Remeber! Remeber!) There is ... what one tells you know, also, my dear, I am confused, I am confused, ... (Just tell! Tell! Remeber!) I am confused over that, I don't remember ... and by God, we don't have these things anymore. There was ... there was a grandmother of mine was telling us fairy tales, do you understand? She kept telling us stories, now we don't remember anything ... [So you know a joke to tell?] </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
        <ANNOTATION>
            <REF_ANNOTATION ANNOTATION_ID="a24" ANNOTATION_REF="a13">
                <ANNOTATION_VALUE>a joke? ... wait, I see this ... now ... there is a, a ... an old lady, an old lady, she comes to her son and keeps saying to him ... she keeps saying to him "Your mother always mokes me, do you understand? She insults me and so on..." He goes to his wife, he tells her: "Look, I will keep beating you, I will beat you and when I start hitting a pillow, only on the pillow, keep shouting. She kept shouting and she said now, she went out to his mother and told him: "You made my heart cold, my son." He told her: "Mama, look, tomorrow I will go, I will lock her in the house and I will let her (there) you ... I leave her, she won't eat" He didn't lock her in the house. He carried her, he took her with him, he took with him his wife. He came in the evening, he told her: "Mother, what is it?" She told him: "YOu left her to me and she was looking down on me from down there since the morning. She insults me from under this door" She was taken by him [...] yeah, that's it. That is the stiry. And I have a lot, its just that I am confused and by God I don't know, I am confused, we dont remember these things. </ANNOTATION_VALUE>
            </REF_ANNOTATION>
        </ANNOTATION>
    </TIER>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="MOR_Z_Gh_39.M" PARTICIPANT="A" TIER_ID="A_Translation-gls-ar"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="MOR_Z_Gh_39.M" PARTICIPANT="A" TIER_ID="A_Participant-note-en"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Text" TIER_ID="Interlinear-title"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Phrases "
        PARTICIPANT="B" TIER_ID="B_Transcription-txt"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Words"
        PARENT_REF="B_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="B" TIER_ID="B_Words-txt"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="B_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="B" TIER_ID="B_Translation-gls-en"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="B_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="B" TIER_ID="B_Translation-gls-ar"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="B_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="B" TIER_ID="B_Participant-note-en"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Phrases "
        PARTICIPANT=" C" TIER_ID="C_Transcription-txt"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Words"
        PARENT_REF="C_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="C" TIER_ID="C-Words-txt"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="C_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="C" TIER_ID="C_Translation-gls-eng"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="C_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="C" TIER_ID="C_Translation-gls-ar"/>
    <TIER ANNOTATOR="Rebecca" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_REF="Note"
        PARENT_REF="C_Transcription-txt" PARTICIPANT="C" TIER_ID="C_Participant-note-en"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Text" TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false"
        LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Phrases " TIME_ALIGNABLE="true"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Subdivision"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Words" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <LINGUISTIC_TYPE CONSTRAINTS="Symbolic_Association"
        GRAPHIC_REFERENCES="false" LINGUISTIC_TYPE_ID="Note" TIME_ALIGNABLE="false"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time subdivision of parent annotation's time interval, no time gaps allowed within this interval" STEREOTYPE="Time_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Symbolic subdivision of a parent annotation. Annotations refering to the same parent are ordered" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Subdivision"/>
    <CONSTRAINT DESCRIPTION="1-1 association with a parent annotation" STEREOTYPE="Symbolic_Association"/>
    <CONSTRAINT
        DESCRIPTION="Time alignable annotations within the parent annotation's time interval, gaps are allowed" STEREOTYPE="Included_In"/>
</ANNOTATION_DOCUMENT>
